Guide to the William S. Deming Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Smith Deming papers
1833-1837
MS 1128
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of seventy-four letters exchanged between William S. Deming and his family and friends during Deming's years at Yale College (1833-1837). Since Deming was poor, many of his letters discuss the expenses of student life. His father's letters from Newington, Connecticut include advise on maintaining his health, family news, and discussions of monetary problems. Included also is a bill from Yale College (1836).
Deming, William Smith, 1815-1839
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Benton L. Hatch, 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This small collection consists of seventy-four letters exchanged by William Smith Deming with his family and a few friends between 1833 and 1837, during his study at Yale College. There is also a notice signed by Wyllys Warner (1836 Oct 31) concerning Deming's unpaid college bills. The papers are arranged in a single chronological sequence.
The letters from Deming's father, William Deming of Newington, Connecticut, and others include advice on maintaining one's health through physical labor and proper diet, family news, and monetary problems. Deming's own letters describe his activities at Yale and go into detail about the expenses of student life. He experienced financial difficulties in maintaining himself at Yale, and received money from his family and the citizens of Newington before leaving college in 1836 to raise money by teaching school in Killingworth, Connecticut.
These papers were given to Yale University in 1955 by Benton L. Hatch. They were formerly part of the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection.
Biographical / Historical
William Smith Deming was born in Newington, Connecticut, on November 27, 1815. He became interested in religion in 1831 and commenced study at Westfield Academy, preparing for work in the gospel ministry. He graduated from Yale College in 1837 and spent the following year at Prospect Hill, Virginia, as a teacher. In August, 1839, he returned to Connecticut in poor health and died on September 14, 1839.
Newington (Conn.); Deming, William Smith; Deming, William, 1792-1865; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1837; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - 1833 Oct-1834 Feb (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1834 Mar-Jul (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1834 Oct-Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1835 Feb-Jul (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1835 Aug-Dec (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1836 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1836 Jun-Aug (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1836 Oct-Nov 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1836 Nov 10-1837 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10 - 13)